<?xml version="1.0"?>
<language>

    <!-- Random: Commonly Used -->
    <string key="unknown">Unknown</string>
    <string key="m_years_old">million years old</string>
    <string key="b_years_old">billion years old</string>
    
    <!-- Menu_StarCreation: Star Descriptions -->
    <string key="desc_o_class">O-type stars are incredibly hot and massive, with temperatures reaching up to 60,000 K. They emit a tremendous amount of ultraviolet radiation and have a very short lifespan, living only a few million years. They are primarily composed of hydrogen and helium. Due to their short lifespan and intense radiation, O-type star systems are less likely to harbor stable, life-supporting planets, but they may have massive gas giants and possibly young, rocky planets in their early stages of formation.</string>
    <string key="desc_b_class">B-type stars are also hot and luminous, with temperatures ranging from 10,000 to 30,000 K. They have a relatively short lifespan compared to other star types, living up to 100 million years. They are primarily composed of hydrogen and helium, with traces of other elements such as carbon and nitrogen. B-type star systems may contain massive gas giants and young terrestrial planets. The intense radiation and stellar winds make it challenging for life to develop, but circumstellar disks can form around these stars, potentially leading to planet formation.</string>
    <string key="desc_a_class">A-type stars have temperatures ranging from 7,500 to 10,000 K, and have a moderate lifespan of around 1 billion years. They are primarily composed of hydrogen and helium, with traces of other elements such as carbon, nitrogen, and oxygen. A-type star systems are likely to have a mix of gas giants and rocky planets. While the radiation is still significant, it is more conducive to the formation of stable planetary orbits, increasing the chances of finding potentially habitable planets, especially in the outer regions of the habitable zone.</string>
    <string key="desc_f_class">F-type stars have temperatures ranging from 6,000 to 7,500 K, and have a longer lifespan of around 3 billion years. They are primarily composed of hydrogen and helium, with traces of other elements such as carbon, nitrogen, oxygen, and iron. F-type star systems often have a diverse range of planets, including gas giants and rocky planets. The habitable zone is wider and more stable, making these systems promising candidates for life-supporting planets. Their moderate radiation levels allow for the development of atmospheres and liquid water on terrestrial planets.</string>
    <string key="desc_g_class">G-type stars, like our sun, have temperatures around 5,500 K and have a lifespan of around 10 billion years. They are primarily composed of hydrogen and helium, with traces of other elements such as carbon, nitrogen, oxygen, and iron. G-type star systems are well-known for hosting a variety of planets, including gas giants and Earth-like rocky planets. The stable and long-lived nature of these stars' habitable zones makes them ideal for the development of complex life. Our own solar system is a prime example, with a diverse range of planets and moons.</string>
    <string key="desc_k_class">K-type stars have temperatures ranging from 3,500 to 5,000 K and have a longer lifespan of around 30 billion years. They are primarily composed of hydrogen and helium, with traces of other elements such as carbon, nitrogen, oxygen, iron, silicon, and magnesium. K-type star systems are very promising for planet formation, with a wide habitable zone that can support both rocky and gas giant planets. Their long lifespans provide ample time for life to potentially evolve. These stars are excellent candidates for hosting Earth-like planets with stable climates.</string>
    <string key="desc_m_class">M-type stars are the coolest and have temperatures of less than 3,500 K. They have a longer lifespan of around 100 billion years and are primarily composed of hydrogen and helium, with traces of other elements such as carbon, nitrogen, oxygen, iron, silicon, and magnesium. M-type star systems are likely to have numerous rocky planets and potentially habitable worlds. Despite their lower energy output, their long lifespans allow for extensive periods of planetary stability. However, their habitable zones are close to the star, which can result in tidal locking and intense stellar flares affecting planetary atmospheres.</string>


</language>
